Liang Mi

699 S. Mill Ave., ASU CIDSE 553 Tempe, Arizona, 85281 http://www.icemiliang.com icemiliang@gmail.com +1 774-262-8824

SUMMARY

I am a Ph.D. candidate at Arizona State University. My research interests lie in the intersection of machine learning and computer vision, particularly in functional mapping and its applications in clustering, embedding learning, domain adaptation, 3D registration, and medical imaging. I am also working on unsupervised depth estimation from monocular color images. I have interned at Bosch and Intuitive Surgical. I am open to a full-time scientist/engineer position focusing on machine learning and computer vision, starting at Spring 2020.

EDUCATION

• Doctor of Philosophy in Computer Engineering, 4.0/4.0 Arizona State University, Tempe, Arizona

Aug. 2014 – Present

 \bullet Master of Science in Electrical and Computer Engineering, 3.8/4.0

May 2014

Worcester Polytechnic Institute, Worcester, Massachusetts
• Bachelor of Engineering in Electrical Engineering, 83.3/100

Jul. 2012

Harbin Institute of Technology, Harbin, China

SKILLS

• Languages: C/C++, Python, Matlab, etc. Libraries: Eigen, ITK/VTK, OpenCV/GL, PyTorch, SciPy, etc.

SELECT WORK EXPERIENCE

• Research Intern (Visual Sensing)

Summer 2019

Bosch, Sunnyvale, California

- **Depth Estimation**: Developed a deep self-supervised learning framework for depth map estimation from monocular color images and sparse LiDAR samples.
- Metric Learning: Developed a deep learning model to find a common embedding space of different modalities for cross-modal object recognition.
- Software Engineering Intern (Imaging and Computer Vision)

Summer 2017

 $Intuitive \ Surgical, \ Sunnyvale, \ California$

• 3D Reconstruction: Designed and implemented an algorithm, in C++, for on-line 3D reconstruction.

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

• Optimization over Variational Optimal Transportation

Sep. 2018 – Present

Geometric Systems Laboratory, Arizona State University

- Regularization: Designing regularized transportation techniques for domain adaptation and skeleton layout.
- Wasserstein Loss: Developing a differential Wasserstein loss for learning Gaussian mixtures and autoencoders.
- Wasserstein Clustering using Variational Principles (ECCV'18, ICCV'17) Sep. 2015 Mar. 2018
 - Clustering: Proposed to solve constraint k-means problem with optimal transportation.
 - Transportation: Implemented 3D variational optimal transportation for computing Wasserstein distances.

• Mesh Completion

Jan. 2015 - May 2015

3D Scanning Laboratory, Stony Brook University

• ICP: Used iterative closest point to register parametric face meshes.

• Virtual Capsule Endoscopy (BodyNets 2013)

Jan. 2013 – Jan. 2014

Center for Wireless Information Networking Studies, Worcester Polytechnic Institute

• Simulation: Created a virtual testbed to simulate capsule endoscopy for validating visual tracking algorithms.

• Building Detection on Aerial LiDAR Images (IST 2013)

Jan. 2012 – May 2012

Institute of Image and Information Processing, Harbin Institute of Technology

- Terran reconstruction: Implemented a reconstruction algorithm by using the minimum description length.
- Building detection: Proposed a two-step detection framework by reconstructing terrain and removing trees.

• Teaching Assistant

Arizona State University

- o Spring 2018: Database Management (SER 322), Logic Design (SER232)
- Fall 2017: Logic In Computer Science (CSE 259, Instructor of recitation sessions)
- Fall 2016: Data Structures and Algorithms (CSE 310, Instructor of recitation sessions)
- Fall 2014: The Principles of Programming Languages (CSE 110)

• Grader

May 2013 - May 2014

Aug. 2014 - Present

Worcester Polytechnic Institute

- Spring 2012: Digital Image Processing (CS/ECE 545)
- o Fall 2011: Introduction to Wireless Networks (ECE 3308)

Related Courses

- Math: Conformal Geometry (ASU), Complex Analysis (Coursera)
- Graphics: Computer Graphics (ASU, WPI), Geometric Modeling (ASU)
- Vision: Digital Image/Video Processing (ASU, WPI), Robotics: Perception (Coursera)
- Machine Learning: Statistical Machine Learning (ASU)
- **Deep**: Neural Networks for Machine Learning (Coursera) Convolutional Neural Networks for Visual Recognition (Stanford Online)

Select Projects

- Loop subdivision: Implemented the Loop subdivision algorithm with the half-edge data structure in C++.
- Conformal maps: Implemented the *spherical conformal mapping* algorithm and the *least squares conformal mapping* algorithm with the half-edge structure in C++.
- Image stitching: Used OpenCV (C++) to stitch panoramic pictures by matching SIFT features.

AWARDS

- Fellowship: ASU Graduate College Completion Fellowship 2019, ASU Engineering Graduate Fellowship 2018, 2019, ASU University College Fellowship 2018
- Travel: Peter Hall Conference Travel Award 2019, ASU Graduate College Travel Award 2017, ASU CIDSE Conference Funding 2017, 2018

SERVICES

• Reviewer: AAAI '20, CVPR '19, ICCV '19, MICCAI '17, '18, '19, IEEE TBME '14, SPIE JARS '14

SELECT PUBLICATIONS

- Mi, Liang, Wen Zhang, and Yalin Wang. "Regularized Wasserstein Means via Variational Transportation" arXiv preprint arXiv:1812.00338. (Preprint)
- Zhang, Wen, Liang Mi, Paul Thompson, and Yalin Wang. "A Geometric Framework for Feature Mappings in Multimodal Fusion of Brain Image Data." In proceedings of the Information Processing in Medical Imaging (IPMI), 2019.
- Mi, Liang, Wen Zhang, Xianfeng Gu, and Yalin Wang. "Variational Wasserstein Clustering." In Proceedings of the European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV), pp. 322-337. 2018.
- Singh, Shibani, Anant Srivastava, Liang Mi, Richard J. Caselli, Kewei Chen, Dhruman Goradia, Eric M. Reiman, and Yalin Wang. "Deep-learning-based classification of FDG-PET data for Alzheimer's disease categories." In 13th International Conference on Medical Information Processing and Analysis, vol. 10572, p. 105720J. International Society for Optics and Photonics, 2017.
- Mi, Liang, Wen Zhang, Junwei Zhang, Yonghui Fan, Dhruman Goradia, Kewei Chen, Eric M. Reiman, Xianfeng Gu, and Yalin Wang. "An Optimal Transportation based Univariate Neuroimaging Index." In Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (ICCV), pp. 182-191. 2017.
- Bao, Guanqun, Kaveh Pahlavan, **Liang Mi**, "Hybrid Localization of Micro-robotic Endoscopic Capsule inside Small Intestine by Data Fusion of Vision and RF Sensors", Sensors Journal, IEEE, Volume:PP, Issue: 99, Nov. 2014.
- Mi, Liang, Shuang Zhou, Hao Chen, Yishuang Geng, Building Detection in Digital Surface Model, Imaging Systems and Techniques (IST), 2013 IEEE International Conference on, Beijing, China, 22-23 Oct. 2013.